Guide to the Armin Dale Kaiser Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Armin Dale Kaiser papers
1956-1982
SC0356
Kaiser, Armin Dale
7 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of A. Dale Kaiser, 1989
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy
Biographical/Historical note
Professor of Biochemistry, Stanford University, 1959-1982. Among the first to investigate the quantitative genetics of bacterial viruses. His studies formed the basis for much of our understanding of how viruses interact with their host cells, and how they may produce cancer. His detailed biochemical investigations of viral genes have clarified their organization in the chromosomes of viruses and much of the mechanisms by which they are often incorporated into the host chromosome
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, 1966-1972; research notebooks, 1956-ca. 1980; and faculty notebooks, 1979-1982
Access Terms
Kaiser, Armin Dale; Stanford University. Department of Biochemistry. Faculty.; Biochemistry; Science--History.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - JMB (Journal of Molecular Biology) correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Laban, Peter (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, 1971 Kaiser (Sept-Dec) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence,, Fall Quarter 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence ADK-1970, A-H (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, I-Q (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, Q-Z (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Faculty Report, 1969, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Report Annual SUpplement, 1966-1967, 1967-1968, Dale Kaiser (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1969 A-H (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kaiser, Personal Papers (incL CUrriculum vitae) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1971 Kaiser, A-H (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1971, I-Q (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1971, R-Z (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1966 and prior, Dale Kaiser (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Casjens, Sherwood (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hendrix, Roger W (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ordal, George (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Reichardt, Louis F (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Spiegelman, willard Gibbs (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Matsubara, Kenichi (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Strack, Hans (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - studier, William (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wake, Robert Gerard (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Irnnan, Ross B (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Record, Mason T (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kayajanian, Gary (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Kuhnlein, Urs (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MacKinlay, Anthony (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Love, William (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Freedman, Roger (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Georgopoulos, Constantin P (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gussin, Gary (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Heineman, Stephen F (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bode, Vernon (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brody, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hohn, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Berg, Douglas (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969, I-Q (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, R-Z (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory Notebook, no date, no title (Box 3)
  - Lab notebook [Serbur Strong Coupling Theory] (Box 3)
  - Lecture Notebook, Enzymology & Chemistry of Nucleotides & Polynucleotides, Lehman 1961 (Box 3)
  - Lecture Notebook Biochemistry 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Lecture Notebook Kaiser stocks, [phage inventoryJ (Box 4)
  - Lecture Notebook, bacterial isolates, c. 1957 (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook, no date, no title, [#VII] (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook, no date, no title, [#VII] (Box 4)
  - Kaiser book VIII (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notes, no date, no title (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook, no date, no title, [A[?J Banaud (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook, P. Barrand, Book II (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook, 18, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook, Autoradiology, A. D. Kaiser, et. al., 1966 Jul (Box 4)
  - Laboratory notebook Earl D. Jacobs, Biology sect III, circa 1953 (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook Research bk. V, A. Kaiser, no date (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook Dale Kaiser, bk. IV, circa 1954 (Box 5)
  - [Corresponclence and. notecard found. in box 5, nbk. 2], 28/9/53-19/3/54 (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook, A. D. Kaiser, Research VI (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook, Bk. III, CIT, May 1951- (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook, Book VII, A [lambda] Genetics, 22/3/54-27/1/55 (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook, Microbiology, Experiments, 12/15/51-4/4/52 (Box 5)
  - Sketch book, Mary Durrell, [needs consJ (Box 5)
  - Laboratory notebook, Phage Experiments, A. Kaiser, 108 Kerchaff, 9/30/50-8/8/51 (Box 5)
  - Laboratory Manual, Cal. Tech., Bio. Chem. 107, 1951 (Box 6)
  - Lecture/Seminar notes, Viruses, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Laboratory Notebook, [lambda] Head Assemb., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Strange B42 Isolates (Box 6)
  - Gary Gussin' s Exonuclear Assays (Box 6)
  - Laboratory Notebook, [lambda] Gen, 54-55 (Box 6)
  - Laboratory notebook C-Reg Gen, 5/15/57-12/5/57 (Box 6)
  - Laboratory notebook #0 Trans'D 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory notebook #1 6/57-3/58 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory notebook Experiments, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory notebook- #3 7/58-3/59 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory notebook Radding 1,2,3 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bk 4 4/59-6/59, st. L., Assay studies Index (Box 7)
  - Laboratory notebook, Giberson, 1962, [needs conservation of slides] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory notebook, Bk 5, 9/59-12/59, 21 transduction DNA uptake (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory notebook, Bk 6, 12/59-5/60, Assay DNA uptake helper infection kinetics, corrli tions (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory notebook, Bk 7, 5/60-9/60, Assay Gal i [lambda] transfonnation (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - #8, 10/60-3/6l (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - #9, 3/61-9/6l (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - #10, 9/61-4/62 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - #11, 4/62-10/62 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - #12, Spm D, 7/61-3/63 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - #13, 11/62-3/63 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bk 14, Spm DNA, 2/63-12/63 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bk 15, Quarters, 5/63-12/63 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ray Wu, 1965-66 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Res 1963 M K & I (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 434 by C, 31/V/62-18/VI/62 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - SUS, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Electron Microscopy, Schnoss II, Apr. 67 -Mar 68 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Schnoss I, Aug. 66-Mar. 67 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Mackinlay, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Mackinlay, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Preps., III, 2/62-4/64 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Preps., II, 9/60-2/62 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - , 63, 64 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Plana, 65-66 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - No title, 1/9/67-10/25/68 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Prep. I, 5/58-9/60 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Coli + A strains sent 2/66-present (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - No title, 5/13/69-4/3/72 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Head Assembly, III, 7/72- (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Head Assembly, 4, 11/72- (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Head Assembly, 5, 5/73- (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Head Assembly, 6, 9/73- (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Ca # Assay (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Head Assembly, II, 4/72-8/72 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Head Assembly, I, 9/71-4-72 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Bk 17 Cohesive ends [lambda] (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Polymerase-Exonuclease, 3/9/66-6/13/67 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Bk XIS CUrving Exps., 10/3/66-11/6/67 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Notebook [fac. meetings, etc.], 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - laboratory Notebook, EM 1965, cambridge (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Notebook, Chromosome Bioch. 211, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Lysogeny" 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Virus Structure Infection, Biochem 102, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Morphogenesis Recognition, A. o. Kaiser. Biochemistry 1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - D. Kaiser, 01 Kerchoff, no date (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1966, Gordon Conf. Lysogeny, Hunt-Morgan (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Polymer Confonnation, P. Flo:ty, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - TernpCrMetab, no date (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Virus structure, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Struc. DNA in Phage, circa 1963 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Phage Biochemistry, 1960-196l (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - ALK Phosphatase, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Laborato:ty Notebook, EM on 0, EDNA, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - D, EDNA Cohesion, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Head Mutants Preparation, tests, lysogenization, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Head Mutant DNA, 1970-1971, Isolation, Infectivity (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - BK 24, Attempts to isolate Cure Mutants, 1/9/68-7/7/69 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Bk #22, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Bk 16, 3H [lambda], BKG Exps. 5/1/64-7/9/64 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Bk 19 & 20, Curving & Breakage Trials, Grosses, 6/17/67-8/30/68 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Curving by [larnbda] bl0, 3/26/68-3/24/69 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Minutes, 1970-1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Business, 1979-1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Business, 9/19/79-9/8/81 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Business, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Business, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)